

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Technical Architect seeking role in Software Development, Web Designing, Project Management, Solution Architecture, Technical Architecture, Disaster Recovery, Requirement Gathering, IT Roadmap, Release Management, Delivery Management, MySQL, Agile, Scrum

Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pursuing Graduation]

Highest Degree: Not Pursuing Graduation [Not

Current Designation: Technical Architect Current Company: Tavant Technologies Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Tech Architect

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services
Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Technical Architect, Software Development, Web Designing, Project Management, Solution Architecture, Technical Architecture, Disaster Recovery, Requirement Gathering, IT Roadmap, Release Management, Delivery Management, MySQL, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Oracle DBA

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

## Summary

Tech-sawy professional with 15 years expertise in software development and web designing using Java and J2EE; offering 5 years of experience in working as SOA Integration Architect

Hold the merit of shouldering responsibilities of software system development as SOA Architect, Program Architect, and Solutions Architect

Pioneered the entire development phase by tracking technical issues and solving problems especially for the issues spanning across multiple programs for Travel, Transport, and logistics (TTL), Data center management, B2B, B2C, and Insurance domain

Leveraged skills in working on:

- Mule OOB components like File Transport, FTP/SFTP Transport, JDBC Connector, and Transaction Manager
- o AMQP Endpoints to connect to RabbitMQ which is a messaging queue
- o Database Connectors to connect with respective systems using Mule ESB
- o Anypoint platform, Mulesoft and API Designer
- o Integrations tools like IBM Data power
- o SOA governance and tools like OER

## **Work Experience**

- Tavant Technologies as Technical Architect Feb 2020 to Till Date
- \* Developing technical architectural frameworks for company systems and architectural solutions based on business requirements
- \* Ensured that technical architectures met performance and security requirements
- \* Responding to technical queries from clients, management and team members and delivering proposed work within timelines and quality specifications
- Mapping client's requirements and providing them the best solutions involving evaluation of options, definition of scope of project, and finalization of project requirements
- Working with various levels of management and users to help define information strategy and ensure its consistency with the overall business strategy
- Implementing process to capture functional design and assisting business team to take educated decisions by explaining technical features
- \* Developing architecture and technical work plan to ensure successful development & implementation of
- \* Managing technical issues and serving as the technical authority for team members throughout issue resolution
- \* Interacting with the senior business and the IT client contacts to provide team leadership and hands-on technical and functional expertise
- \* Identifying and collaborating with key stakeholders across the organization to gain buy in and support to execute against developed plan
- \* Monitoring project progress as per scheduled deadlines for various tasks and taking necessary steps to ensure completion within time, cost and effort parameters

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- Providing technical guidance & assistance to teams through full product lifecycles; managing day-to-day activities of the development team(s) including performance appraisal, coaching, mentoring and cross training; providing technical guidance and leadership to fellow team members in area of expertise
- \* Managing various technical aspects like software design, coding of modules, monitoring critical paths & taking appropriate actions
- \* Ensuring that the project delivery team structure is adequate and enforces compliance, best practices, approach & direction for the technical aspects of the organization's practice
- Cognizant as Senior Technical Architect Jul 2014 to Feb 2020
- iTech US as Senior Technical Architect May 2013 to Jun 2014

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

UG: Not Pursuing Graduation (Not Pursuing Graduation)

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Oracle Cloud Platform Application Integration

^ Back to Top

#### **IT Skills**

| Skill Name                        | Version Last Used Experience |
|-----------------------------------|------------------------------|
| Oracle SOA, IBM Data Power XI50   |                              |
| XI52, Mulesoft                    |                              |
| Oracle BAM, Oracle BTM, OEM       |                              |
| Jdeveloper, RAD, Anypoint Studio  |                              |
| Jasper, Oracle BAM                |                              |
| Oracle, DB2, MySQL and SQL Server |                              |
| Oracle, DB2, MySQL and SQL Server |                              |
| Anypoint Studio, Mulesoft         |                              |
| Struts, Spring                    |                              |

^ Back to Top

### Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  | Proficient  | ✓    | ✓     | ✓     |

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No** 

US Work Status: Have H1 Visa

lo Countries: Canada
Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.